Inventory of the William R. Kintner papers, 1951-1986
Hoover Institution Archives
William R. Kintner papers, 1951-1986
81082
Kintner, William R.
93 manuscript boxes (37.2 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
The William R. Kintner papers document the career of an important American foreign policy analyst whose career spanned the Cold War. The bulk of the papers consists of correspondence, much of it deriving from Kintner's leadership role in the Foreign Policy Research Institute, where he served first as director and then as president. In addition to routine correspondence pertaining to the workings of the institute, the collection also has important exchanges of letters between Kintner and other foreign policy experts, including Henry Kissinger and Walt W. Rostow. The papers also contain many of Kintner's writings, including drafts of his monograph, Soviet Global Strategy.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection stored off site; a minimum of two days notice is required for use.
Boxes may be requested through Stanford's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1981.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
1915 Born, Lock Haven, Pennsylvania
1940 Awarded bachelor's degree by the U.S. Military Academy at West Point
1940-1961 Served in the U.S. Army, retiring with the rank of colonel
1949 Received Ph.D. from Georgetown University
1950 The Front Is Everywhere
1961-1985 Professor of political science, University of
1969-1973 Director, Foreign Policy Research Institute
1973-1975 U.S. ambassador to Thailand
1976-1982 President, Foreign Policy Research Institute
1987 Soviet Global Strategy
1997 Died
Scope and Content of Collection
The William R. Kintner papers document the career of an important American foreign policy analyst whose career spanned the Cold War. The bulk of the papers consists of correspondence, much of it deriving from Kintner's leadership role in the Foreign Policy Research Institute, where he served first as director and then as president. In addition to routine correspondence pertaining to the workings of the institute, the collection also has important exchanges of letters between Kintner and other foreign policy experts, including Henry Kissinger and Walt W. Rostow. The papers also contain many of Kintner's writings, including drafts of his monograph, Soviet Global Strategy.
Kintner was an advocate of a strong military posture for the United States and achieved his greatest influence during the Nixon and Reagan administrations. A critic of détente and an opponent of nuclear disarmament, Kintner advanced his views through numerous articles, position papers, and reports, many of which can be found in the papers. In addition to his work as a foreign policy analyst, Kintner was a professor of political science at the University of Pennsylvania, and the papers contain materials relating to his teaching career. There are also briefing papers in the collection that were prepared for Kintner when he was appointed in 1973 as U.S. ambassador to Thailand.
Arrangement
The collection is not arranged.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Foreign Policy Research Institute.; World politics--1945-1989.; United States--Foreign relations--1945-1989.; United States--Military policy.
Collection Contents
- Correspondence, 1959-1970 (Folder 1-8)
  - T, 1969-1970 (Folder 1: 1-2)
    - 1969 (Folder 1: 1)
    - 1970 (Folder 1: 2)
  - Trudeau, Arthur, 1959-1967 (Folder 1: 3)
  - U, 1961-1969 (Folder 1: 4)
  - V, 1963-1970 (Folder 1: 5-7)
    - 1963-1967 (Folder 1: 5)
    - 1969 (Folder 1: 6)
    - 1970 (Folder 1: 7)
  - Wallace, George, 1965-1968 (Folder 1: 8)
  - Ward, Chester, 1963-1969 (Folder 1: 9)
  - Ware, Richard, 1967-1970 (Folder 1: 10-12)
    - 1967 (Folder 1: 10)
    - 1968-1969 (Folder 1: 11)
    - 1970 (Folder 1: 12)
  - Walker, Richard, 1963-1970 (Folder 2: 1-2)
    - 1963-1968 (Folder 2: 1)
    - 1970 (Folder 2: 2)
  - W, 1967-1970 (Folder 2: 3-5)
    - 1967 (Folder 2: 3)
    - 1969 (Folder 2: 4)
    - 1970 (Folder 2: 5)
  - X, Y, Z, 1962-1967 (Folder 2: 6)
  - Zawodny, Jay, 1964-1969 (Folder 3: 1-2)
    - 1964-1967 (Folder 3: 1)
    - 1967-1969 (Folder 3: 2)
  - A, 1963-1970 (Folder 3-4)
    - 1963-1965 (Folder 3: 3)
    - 1966 (Folder 3: 4)
    - 1967-1968 (Folder 3: 5)
    - 1968-1969 (Folder 3: 6)
    - 1970 (Folder 4: 1)
  - Abshire, David, 1962-1968 (Folder 4: 2)
  - Adams, Benson, 1968-1969 (Folder 4: 3)
  - American Academic Association for Peace in the Middle East, 1968-1969 (Folder 4: 4)
  - American Behavioral Scientist, 1967-1969 (Folder 4: 5)
  - Americans for Winning the Peace, 1970 (Folder 4: 6-7)
  - B, 1962-1970 (Folder 5-6)
    - 1962-1966 (Folder 5: 1)
    - 1966-1967 (Folder 5: 2)
    - 1967-1968 (Folder 5: 3)
    - 1969 (Folder 5: 4)
    - 1970 (Folder 6: 1)
  - Barnett, Frank R., 1963-1969 (Folder 6: 2-4)
    - 1963-1966 (Folder 6: 2)
    - 1967-1968 (Folder 6: 3)
    - 1968-1969 (Folder 6: 4)
  - Bebler, Anton, 1967 (Folder 6: 5)
  - Beilenson, Laurence W., 1967-1969 (Folder 6: 6-7)
    - 1967-1968 (Folder 6: 6)
    - 1968-1969 (Folder 6: 7)
  - Bell, Allyn R., Jr., 1963-1969 (Folder 6: 8)
  - Bell Telephone Co., 1960-1963 (Folder 7: 1)
  - Bendetsen, Karl, 1962-1969 (Folder 7: 2)
  - Berlinski, Paul, 1967-1968 (Folder 7: 3)
  - Bjelajac, Slavko, 1968-1969 (Folder 7: 4)
  - Bobrow, David B., 1967-1969 (Folder 7: 5)
  - Boyd, Gavin, 1964-1970 (Folder 7: 6)
  - Brookings Institution, 1960-1966 (Folder 7: 7)
  - Burke, Arleigh, 1964-1969 (Folder 8: 1)
  - C, 1963-1970 (Folder 8: 2-4)
    - 1963-1966 (Folder 8: 2)
    - 1968-1969 (Folder 8: 3)
    - 1970 (Folder 8: 4)
- Speaking engagements, 1967-1973 (Folder 9-12)
  - Not attended, 1967-1973 (Folder 9: 1-2)
    - 1967-1971 (Folder 9: 1)
    - 1971-1973 (Folder 9: 2)
  - Correspondence, 1969-1973 (Folder 9-11)
    - 1969 (Folder 9: 3-4)
    - 1971 (Folder 10: 1-2)
    - 1972 (Folder 11: 1)
    - 1973 (Folder 11: 2)
  - Expenses, 1970-1972 (Folder 11-12)
    - 1970-1971 (Folder 11: 3)
    - 1971 (Folder 12: 1)
    - 1971-1972 (Folder 12: 2)
    - 1972 (Folder 12: 3)
- Royalty statements, 1964-1972 (Folder 12: 4)
- Correspondence, 1969-1972 (Folder 12-15)
  - Personal, 1969-1970 (Folder 12-13)
    - 1969 (Folder 12: 5)
    - 1970 (Folder 13: 1)
  - A, 1972 (Folder 13: 2)
  - B, 1972 (Folder 13: 3)
  - C, 1972 (Folder 13: 4)
  - D, 1972 (Folder 13: 5)
  - E, 1972 (Folder 14: 1)
  - F, 1972 (Folder 14: 2)
  - G, 1972 (Folder 14: 3)
  - H, 1972 (Folder 14: 4)
  - J, 1972 (Folder 14: 5)
  - K, 1972 (Folder 14: 6)
  - L, 1972 (Folder 15: 1)
  - M, 1972 (Folder 15: 2)
- Trip reports and related correspondence, 1970-1973 (Folder 15-19)
  - Canada, 1970 (Folder 15: 3)
  - Europe, 1970 (Folder 15: 4-5)
  - Jamaica, 1971 (Folder 16: 1)
  - Far East, 1971 (Folder 16: 2-4)
  - Europe, 1972 (Folder 17: 1-5)
  - Jamaica and Venezuela, 1972 (Folder 18: 1)
  - Soviet Union, 1972 (Folder 18: 2-4)
  - Israel, 1973 (Folder 18: 5)
  - Brazil, 1973 (Folder 19: 1-2)
- Foreign Policy Research Institute materials, 1957-1971 (Folder 19-20)
  - Memoranda, 1962-1971 (Folder 19: 3-5)
    - 1962-1968 (Folder 19: 3)
    - 1968-1970 (Folder 19: 4)
    - 1968-1971 (Folder 19: 5)
  - Fundraising, 1957-1966 (Folder 20: 1)
  - Office space, 1966-1969 (Folder 20: 2)
  - Research assistant program, 1967-1969 (Folder 20: 3)
  - Future plans, 1969 (Folder 20: 4)
- Correspondence, 1958-1970 (Folder 21-23)
  - Frank, Joseph, 1958-1967 (Folder 21: 1)
  - Freedom House, 1969-1970 (Folder 21: 2-3)
    - 1969 (Folder 21: 2)
    - 1970 (Folder 21: 3)
  - G, 1963-1970 (Folder 21-22)
    - 1963-1966 (Folder 21: 4)
    - 1966-1967 (Folder 21: 5)
    - 1967 (Folder 21: 6)
    - 1968-1969 (Folder 22: 1)
    - 1970 (Folder 22: 2)
  - Gallois, Pierre, 1967-1969 (Folder 22: 3)
  - General Motors, Allison Division, 1962-1967 (Folder 22: 4)
  - Geneste, Marc E., 1963-1969 (Folder 22: 5)
  - German consul, 1967-1968 (Folder 22: 6)
  - Goddard, David R., 1966-1969 (Folder 22: 7)
  - Gorden, Morton, 1968-1969 (Folder 22: 8)
  - Green, Andrew, 1969-1970 (Folder 22: 9)
  - Gross, Feliks, 1968-1969 (Folder 23: 1)
  - H, 1961-1963 (Folder 23: 2)
- Foreign Policy Research Institute materials, 1964-1970 (Folder 23-27)
  - Research proposals, 1969 (Folder 23: 3-4)
  - Research proposals, 1969-1970 (Folder 24: 1-5)
  - Conference proposal, 1970 (Folder 24: 6)
  - Conference and symposium papers, programs and proposals, 1967-1969 (Folder 25: 1-8)
  - Research proposals and reports, 1969-1970 (Folder 26: 1-11)
  - Research proposals and reports, 1964-1969 (Folder 27: 1-14)
- Correspondence, 1955-1973 (Folder 28-53)
  - Ekvall, Robert, 1958-1971 (Folder 28: 1)
  - Findlay, Paul, 1964-1973 (Folder 28: 2)
  - Fisher, John M., 1963-1971 (Folder 28: 3)
  - Fletcher School of Law and Diplomacy, 1971-1973 (Folder 28: 4-5)
    - 1971-1972 (Folder 28: 4)
    - 1971-1973 (Folder 28: 5)
  - Foster, Richard B., 1969-1973 (Folder 28-29)
    - 1969-1970 (Folder 28: 6)
    - 1971-1972 (Folder 28: 7)
    - 1970-1973 (Folder 29: 1)
  - Freedom House, 1971-1973 (Folder 29: 2-4)
    - 1971 (Folder 29: 2)
    - 1972 (Folder 29: 3)
    - 1973 (Folder 29: 4)
  - Frisbee, John, 1963-1971 (Folder 30: 1)
  - Gallois, Pierre, 1970 (Folder 30: 2)
  - Gelber, Harry, 1971-1973 (Folder 30: 3)
  - Geneste, Marc, 1969-1972 (Folder 30: 4)
  - Geyelin, Henry R., 1971 (Folder 30: 5)
  - Ghebhardt, Alexander, 1971-1973 (Folder 30: 6)
  - Glantz, Michael, 1971 (Folder 31: 1)
  - Glaser, Kurt, 1971 (Folder 31: 2)
  - Goddard, David R., 1970 (Folder 31: 3)
  - Goldwater, Barry, 1971 (Folder 31: 4)
  - Gordon, Morton, 1965-1972 (Folder 31: 5)
  - Green, Andrew, 1971-1972 (Folder 31: 6)
  - Gross, Feliks, 1969-1973 (Folder 31: 7)
  - H, 1966-1968 (Folder 31-32)
    - 1966-1967 (Folder 31: 8)
    - 1968 (Folder 31: 9)
    - 1969 (Folder 32: 1)
    - 1970 (Folder 32: 2)
  - Hannon, Stuart L., 1967 (Folder 32: 3)
  - Harlow, Bryce, 1962-1969 (Folder 32: 4)
  - Harnwell, Gaylord P., 1965-1969 (Folder 32: 5)
  - Hitchcock, William K., 1968-1969 (Folder 32: 6)
  - Hobstetter, John N., 1967-1969 (Folder 32: 7)
  - Horlacher, John P., 1965-1967 (Folder 32: 8)
  - Hudson Institute, 1962-1969 (Folder 33: 1-2)
    - 1962-1966 (Folder 33: 1)
    - 1967-1969 (Folder 33: 2)
  - Hutchinson, Charles E., 1968-1969 (Folder 33: 3)
  - I, 1958-1970 (Folder 33: 4-6)
    - 1958-1967 (Folder 33: 4)
    - 1968-1969 (Folder 33: 5)
    - 1970 (Folder 33: 6)
  - Institute for American Strategy, 1961-1963 (Folder 33: 7)
  - Inter-American Defense College, 1968-1969 (Folder 33: 8)
  - Israeli consulate, New York City, 1967-1969 (Folder 33: 9)
  - Iwashima, Hisao, 1966-1969 (Folder 34: 1)
  - J, 1966-1970 (Folder 34: 2-4)
    - 1966-1968 (Folder 34: 2)
    - 1969 (Folder 34: 3)
    - 1970 (Folder 34: 4)
  - Jackson, Henry M., 1959-1969 (Folder 34: 5)
  - James, Daniel, 1965-1969 (Folder 34: 6-7)
    - 1965-1966 (Folder 34: 6)
    - 1967-1969 (Folder 34: 7)
  - K, 1967-1970 (Folder 34-35)
    - 1967-1968 (Folder 34: 8)
    - 1968-1969 (Folder 35: 1)
    - 1970 (Folder 35: 2)
  - Kissinger, Henry, 1955-1969 (Folder 35: 3)
  - Klaiber, Wolfgang, 1968-1970 (Folder 35: 4)
  - Kornfeder, Joseph, 1959-1964 (Folder 35: 5)
  - Air Force, United States, 1971-1973 (Folder 36: 1)
  - Allen, Richard, 1968-1973 (Folder 36: 2)
  - Alsop, Joseph, 1971-1973 (Folder 36: 3)
  - AmaraSingham, Saha, 1973 (Folder 36: 4)
  - American Academic Association for Peace in the Middle East, 1969-1973 (Folder 36: 5)
  - American-Asian Educational Exchange, 1967-1969 (Folder 36: 6)
  - American Assembly, 1970-1972 (Folder 36: 7)
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science, 1968-1969 (Folder 36: 8)
  - American Enterprise Institute, 1971-1973 (Folder 36: 9)
  - Americans for Winning the Peace, 1970-1971 (Folder 36: 10)
  - Army, United States, 1971-1973 (Folder 36: 11)
  - Barnett, Frank, 1969-1973 (Folder 37: 1)
  - Bjelajac, Slavko, 1969-1971 (Folder 37: 2)
  - Board of Foreign Scholarship, 1971-1973 (Folder 37: 3-4)
    - General, 1971-1973 (Folder 37: 3)
    - Bicentennial, 1971-1973 (Folder 37: 4)
  - Bonesteel, Charles, 1963-1968 (Folder 37: 5)
  - Bouscaren, Anthony, 1963-1973 (Folder 37: 6)
  - Boyd, Gavin, 1967-1972 (Folder 37: 7)
  - Brzezinski, Zbigniew, 1971 (Folder 38: 1)
  - Burke, Arleigh, 1970-1972 (Folder 38: 2)
  - Byrne, Charles, 1971-1973 (Folder 38: 3)
  - Center for Strategic Studies, 1971-1973 (Folder 38: 4)
  - Center for the Study of the Presidency, 1973 (Folder 38: 5)
  - Chellis, Genevieve V. de, 1973 (Folder 38: 6)
  - Cherne, Leo, 1972-1973 (Folder 38: 7)
  - Clutterbuck, R. L., 1971-1972 (Folder 38: 8)
  - Coste, Brutus, 1969-1971 (Folder 38: 9)
  - Council against Communist Aggression, 1971-1972 (Folder 38: 10)
  - Council of the Americas, 1971 (Folder 38: 11)
  - Council on Foreign Relations, 1971-1973 (Folder 38: 12)
  - Damien, George D., 1970-1973 (Folder 39: 1-2)
  - Davies, James, 1969-1970 (Folder 39: 3)
  - Davis, Paul, 1959-1972 (Folder 39: 4)
  - Davis, Vincent, 1970-1971 (Folder 39: 5)
  - Drummond, Roscoe, 1967-1972 (Folder 39: 6)
  - Dubberstein, Waldo H., 1971 (Folder 39: 7)
  - Durbrow, Elbridge, 1971 (Folder 39: 8)
  - L, 1967-1970 (Folder 40: 1-3)
    - 1967-1968 (Folder 40: 1)
    - 1968-1969 (Folder 40: 2)
    - 1970 (Folder 40: 3)
  - Leibman, Morris, 1963-1969 (Folder 40: 4-5)
    - 1963-1967 (Folder 40: 4)
    - 1968-1969 (Folder 40: 5)
  - Litton Industries, 1967 (Folder 40: 6)
  - Lodge, John Davis, 1964-1967 (Folder 40: 7)
  - Lottinville, Savoie, 1960-1967 (Folder 40: 8)
  - M, 1968-1970 (Folder 41: 1-3)
    - 1968 (Folder 41: 1)
    - 1969 (Folder 41: 2)
    - 1970 (Folder 41: 3)
  - Mandel, Benjamin, 1962-1967 (Folder 41: 4)
  - Mangold, K. P., 1964-1965 (Folder 41: 5)
  - Marsh, John O., 1963-1969 (Folder 41: 6)
  - McMichael, R. Daniel, 1963-1970 (Folder 41: 7-9)
    - 1963-1966 (Folder 41: 7)
    - 1967-1969 (Folder 41: 8)
    - 1970 (Folder 41: 9)
  - Moore, Ben T., 1970 (Folder 42: 1)
  - Munk, Frank, 1963-1965 (Folder 42: 2)
  - N, 1967-1970 (Folder 42: 3-5)
    - 1967-1968 (Folder 42: 3)
    - 1968-1969 (Folder 42: 4)
    - 1970 (Folder 42: 5)
  - Neff, John C., 1967 (Folder 42: 6)
  - New York Times, 1965-1968 (Folder 42: 7)
  - Nixon, Richard M., 1970-1971 (Folder 42: 8)
    Includes articles, press releases, and speeches
  - O, 1966-1969 (Folder 42: 9-10)
    - 1966-1967 (Folder 42: 9)
    - 1968-1969 (Folder 42: 10)
  - Office of Research Administration, University of Pennsylvania, 1967-1971 (Folder 43: 1)
  - Orbis, 1967-1970 (Folder 43: 2-4)
    - 1967-1969 (Folder 43: 2)
    - 1970 (Folder 43: 3)
    - 1971 (Folder 43: 4)
  - P, 1968-1970 (Folder 43: 5-7)
    - 1968 (Folder 43: 5)
    - 1969 (Folder 43: 6)
    - 1970 (Folder 43: 7)
  - Perry, Bruce, 1964-1968 (Folder 44: 1-3)
    - 1964-1965 (Folder 44: 1)
    - 1966-1967 (Folder 44: 2)
    - 1968 (Folder 44: 3)
  - Petrov, Vladimir, 1962-1966 (Folder 44: 4)
  - Pfaltzgraff, Robert L., 1969-1970 (Folder 44-45)
    - 1969 (Folder 44: 5-6)
    - 1970 (Folder 45: 1)
  - Possony, Stefan T., 1963-1970 (Folder 45: 2-5)
    - 1963-1966 (Folder 45: 2)
    - 1967 (Folder 45: 3)
    - 1968-1969 (Folder 45: 4)
    - 1970 (Folder 45: 5)
  - R, 1968-1970 (Folder 45: 6-7)
    - 1968-1969 (Folder 45: 6)
    - 1970 (Folder 45: 7)
  - Regnery, Henry, 1962-1966 (Folder 46: 1)
  - Rosenbaum, Brenda Z., 1965 (Folder 46: 2)
  - Rostow, Walt W., 1963-1969 (Folder 46: 3)
  - Rubinstein, Alvin Z., 1968-1969 (Folder 46: 4)
  - S, 1966-1970 (Folder 46-47)
    - 1966-1967 (Folder 46: 5)
    - 1967-1968 (Folder 46: 6)
    - 1969 (Folder 47: 1)
    - 1970 (Folder 47: 2)
  - Scott, Harriet Fast, 1966-1967 (Folder 47: 3)
  - Shaw, Edward, 1967-1968 (Folder 47: 4)
  - Stanford Research Institute, 1960-1966 (Folder 47-48)
    - 1960-1963 (Folder 47: 5)
    - 1963-1966 (Folder 48: 1)
  - Steinman Foundation, 1967-1969 (Folder 48: 2)
  - Strausz-Hupé, Robert, 1967-1970 (Folder 48: 3-5)
    - 1967 (Folder 48: 3)
    - 1968-1969 (Folder 48: 4)
    - 1970 (Folder 48: 5)
  - C, 1965-1967 (Folder 49: 1)
  - Center on Peace Research and Conflict Resolution, 1970 (Folder 49: 2)
  - Central Intelligence Agency, 1965-1968 (Folder 49: 3)
  - Coste, Brutus, 1959-1969 (Folder 49: 4)
  - Council against Communist Aggression, 1963-1969 (Folder 49: 5-6)
    - 1963-1964 (Folder 49: 5)
    - 1965-1969 (Folder 49: 6)
  - Council on Foreign Relations, 1963-1969 (Folder 50: 1-3)
    - 1963-1964 (Folder 50: 1)
    - 1965-1967 (Folder 50: 2)
    - 1968-1969 (Folder 50: 3)
  - Crane, Robert D., 1968-1969 (Folder 50: 4)
  - Critchfield, Richard, 1969 (Folder 50: 5)
  - Cutler, Neal E., 1968-1969 (Folder 50: 6)
  - D, 1963-1970 (Folder 51: 1-5)
    - 1963-1966 (Folder 51: 1)
    - 1966-1967 (Folder 51: 2)
    - 1968 (Folder 51: 3)
    - 1969 (Folder 51: 4)
    - 1970 (Folder 51: 5)
  - Damien, George, 1966-1969 (Folder 52: 1-2)
    - 1966-1968 (Folder 52: 1)
    - 1968-1969 (Folder 52: 2)
  - Davey, William, 1963-1965 (Folder 52: 3)
  - Department of State (U.S.), 1965-1969 (Folder 52: 4)
  - Dodd, Thomas J., 1962-1967 (Folder 52: 5-6)
    - 1962-1966 (Folder 52: 5)
    - 1967 (Folder 52: 6)
  - Dupuy, Trevor N., 1964-1965 (Folder 52: 7)
  - E, 1966-1970 (Folder 52: 8-11)
    - 1966 (Folder 52: 8)
    - 1967-1968 (Folder 52: 9)
    - 1968-1969 (Folder 52: 10)
    - 1970 (Folder 52: 11)
  - F, 1966-1970 (Folder 53: 1-4)
    - 1966 (Folder 53: 1)
    - 1967-1968 (Folder 53: 2)
    - 1968-1969 (Folder 53: 3)
    - 1970 (Folder 53: 4)
  - Fisher, Sydney, 1962-1969 (Folder 53: 5)
  - Foster, Richard B., 1959-1969 (Folder 53: 6-7)
    - 1959-1966 (Folder 53: 6)
    - 1967-1969 (Folder 53: 7)
- Speeches and Writings, 1952-1973 (Folder 53-58)
  - "Academic Freedom and Classified Research,", 1966 (Folder 53: 8)
  - "American Responsibilities in the Nuclear Age,", 1956 (Folder 53: 9)
  - "Arms Race, No; R&D Race, Yes,", 1970 (Folder 53: 10)
  - "Atlantic Science Potentialities,", 1966-1967 (Folder 53: 11)
  - Atomic Weapons in Land Combat, 1953 (Folder 53: 12)
    Reviews only
  - "Calley Reaction Analyzed,", 1971 (Folder 53: 13)
  - "The Case against International Control of Weapons,", 1964 (Folder 53: 14)
  - "Current Strategic Thinking and Military Theory in the Communist World,", 1963-1964 (Folder 53: 15)
  - "Debacle Road,", 1968 (Folder 53: 16)
  - Discussion on U.S.-Soviet relations, 1968 (Folder 53: 17)
  - Eastern Europe and European Security, 1971 (Folder 53: 18)
    Correspondence only
  - "The Emerging Nixon Doctrine: Toward a New International Structure,", 1972 (Folder 54: 1)
  - "A Few Observations about the U.S. Global Situation,", 1970 (Folder 54: 2)
  - "Filching versus Faking,", 1971 (Folder 54: 3)
  - "Forging a New Sword,", 1958 (Folder 54: 4)
  - "Freedom of the Press Is not Absolute,", 1971 (Folder 54: 5)
  - "Has the Soviet Military Threat Ended?", 1967 (Folder 54: 6)
  - The Impact of President Nixon's Visit to Peking on International Politics, 1972 (Folder 54: 7)
  - "The Insidious Campaign to Silence Anti-Communists,", 1962 (Folder 54: 8)
  - "The Issues as Viewed by McGovern,", 1968 (Folder 54: 9)
  - "Japan and the U.S.-New Directions,", 1968 (Folder 54: 10)
  - "A Leap into the Unknown,", 1968 (Folder 54: 11)
  - "The Military as an Element of Soviet State Power,", 1955 (Folder 54: 12)
  - "Military Situation in Europe,", 1972 (Folder 54: 13)
  - "The Nature and Costs of United States Overseas Commitments,", 1969 (Folder 54: 14)
  - The New Frontier of War, 1962 (Folder 55: 1)
  - "Nixon Used Blockade to Bolster America's Global Srength,", 1972 (Folder 55: 2)
  - "Nixon's Peking Trip: Outlook Is Debated,", 1971 (Folder 55: 3)
  - The Nuclear Revolution in Soviet Military Affairs, 1968 (Folder 55: 4)
  - "The Orchestration of Crisis,", 1961 (Folder 55: 5)
  - "Organizing for Conflict: A Proposal,", 1958 (Folder 55: 6)
  - Peace and the Strategy Conflict, 1967 (Folder 55: 7)
  - "Political Implications of the Soviet Withdrawal from Egypt,", 1973 (Folder 55: 8)
  - "The Politicalization of Strategy,", 1963 (Folder 55: 9)
  - "The Politicalization of Strategy,", 1965 (Folder 55: 10)
  - "The President and Thermonuclear War,", 1961 (Folder 55: 11)
  - "The President and Thermonuclear War,", 1961 (Folder 55: 11)
  - "Progress in Defense Organization,", 1960 (Folder 55: 12)
  - "The Prospects for Western Science and Technology,", 1965 (Folder 56: 1)
  - The Prudent Case for Safeguard, 1969 (Folder 56: 2)
  - "The Purloined Pentagon Papers,", 1971 (Folder 56: 3)
  - "A Reappraisal of the Proposed Nonproliferation Treaty,", 1966 (Folder 56: 4)
  - "The Relation between Power and Values in the Nuclear Age,", 1966 (Folder 56: 5)
  - Safeguard: Why the ABM Makes Sense, 1969 (Folder 56: 6)
  - "The Sane Case for U.S. Safeguard ABM Deployment,", 1969 (Folder 56: 7)
  - "Sécurité européenne: un point de vue amricain,", 1972 (Folder 56: 8)
  - Statement in support of the Freedom Commission Act, 1963 (Folder 56: 9)
  - "Studying Caribbean Development: Two Modes of Approach,", 1966 (Folder 56: 10)
  - "Technology and International Politics: The Crisis of Wishing,", 1971 (Folder 56: 11)
  - "A Threat to American Industry,", 1963 (Folder 56: 12)
  - "The Uncertain Strategic Balance in the 1970s,", 1969 (Folder 56: 13)
  - "Unwrapping the McGovern Defense Package,", 1972 (Folder 56: 14)
  - "The U.S. and the USSR: Conflict and Cooperation,", 1973 (Folder 56: 15)
  - "Vietnam Survey,", 1972 (Folder 56: 16)
  - "The Warsaw Pact and Western Security,", 1967 (Folder 57: 1)
  - "What Is Enough?", 1972 (Folder 57: 2)
  - "Will We Dominate Half of the Earth?", 1968 (Folder 57: 3)
  - Addresses, speeches, and lectures, 1952-1971 (Folder 57: 4)
  - Correspondence relating to articles by William R. Kintner, 1965-1971 (Folder 57: 5-6)
  - Book reviews written by William R. Kintner, 1961-1973 (Folder 58: 1-3)
    - 1961-1966 (Folder 58: 1)
    - 1968 (Folder 58: 2)
    - 1972-1973 (Folder 58: 3)
  - Letters to the editor, 1967-1972 (Folder 58: 4)
- Photographs, 1961-1969 (Folder 58: 5)
- Briefing papers for confirmation hearings regarding Kintner's appointment as ambassador to Thailand, 1973 (Folder 58: 6-7)
- Correspondence, 1951-1986 (Folder 59-89)
  - Makinsky, Alexander, 1970-1971 (Folder 59: 1)
  - Marrero, J. Edward, 1971-1973 (Folder 59: 2)
  - McGovern, George, 1972 (Folder 59: 3)
  - Meyerson, Martin, 1970-1973 (Folder 59: 4)
  - National War College, 1972 (Folder 59: 5)
  - Nellen, Eugene H., 1971 (Folder 59: 6)
  - New York Times, 1968-1972 (Folder 59: 7)
  - Nixon, Richard M., 1967-1972 (Folder 59: 8-11)
    - Correspondence, 1967-1972 (Folder 59: 8-9)
      - 1967-1970 (Folder 59: 8)
      - 1971-1972 (Folder 59: 9)
    - Press releases and statements, 1970-1972 (Folder 59: 10-11)
      - 1970-1971 (Folder 59: 10)
      - 1972 (Folder 59: 11)
  - Orbis, 1971-1973 (Folder 60: 1-3)
    - 1971 (Folder 60: 1)
    - 1972 (Folder 60: 2)
    - 1973 (Folder 60: 3)
  - Orr, David W., 1972 (Folder 61: 1)
  - Ørvik, Nils, 1971 (Folder 61: 2)
  - Ostrich, Ralph, 1970 (Folder 61: 3)